konna koto ii na   dekitara ii na
I wish I had this...   I wish I could do that...
anna yume konna yume  ippai aru kedo
This kind of dream, that kind of dream... There are lots of kinds, but...
minna minna minna   kanaete kureru
Each and every one of them can come true!
fushigi na pokke de kanaete kureru
With his mysterious pocket, he'll make all your dreams come true!
sora wo jiyuu ni tobitai na
I'd sure like to fly about freely in the sky...
"hai! take koputaa"
"All right! Bamboo 'Copter!"
an an an  tottemo daisuki Doraemon
Oh, oh, oh... I love you so much, Doraemon!
The Time Cloth
"The Time Cloth!"
We, Team Nothing Better to Do, have taken over your pathetic preschool!
That's enough from you,
Team Nothing Better to Do!
Who the heck are you?!
I am the Space Sergeant!
Wonder if it's gonna die yet?
I think it's about to.
Yay!
It finally broke!
Hey, Mom!
Mom! The TV broke.
What?!
Ta-da!
Oh, this thing...
See?
Let's jump at this chance and go buy a new one!
A really big one!
Augh, that hurt!
See?
I found out lately that it'll still work once you hit it around here at about a 60 degree angle.
Oh... I wonder if we'll need to buy
a new one of these pretty soon, too.
Uh, oh...
Oh, Honey~!
Um, you know...
Perfect timing. I'm thinking
about getting a new camera.
Our washer's more important
than something like that!
Our washer?
It still works, so isn't it fine for now?
Oh! Uh, well... New ones
have all these nice features and...
Here's my finishing move...!
Oh, there it goes again.
Come on...
If you hit it, it works for a little while, but...
Again...?!
Come on, that TV really  doesn't work anymore.
A camera!
A washer!
The shutter on this one
doesn't work right anymore.
We have laundry that needs
washed everyday, you know?
I need to be able to take pictures when I want to! They become special memories, after all...
Looks like a new TV's out of the question right now.
Oh, well. Let's fix the one we have now.
What? You can do that?
Of course! Let's see here...
Time Cloth
Because we have the Time Cloth!
Just watch! We wrap it in this...
And voilà!
Wow! It's like it's brand new!
That's because it goes back to
how it used to be when you wrap it in this.
This is awesome!
Hey, I know!
I'll fix the washer for Mom, too!
Oh, no! You've got it inside out!
What?! It's all worn out and beat up...
That's because things get older if you put it on backwards.
There we go!
And... That should do it!
Oh, my!
What happened to our washer?!
It sparkles just like the day we bought it!
What do you think? Pretty
awesome that it's just like new, isn't it?!
This sure is a handy cloth!
I know! How about we gather up
everyone's old stuff they don't need...
Oh, I get it! If we make it all
new again with the Time Cloth...
We can get toys or anything for free!
If you have any old stuff you don't need, can we have it?
Here you go.
Thanks!
What are you going to do with all that?
Oh, just something.
Suneo-kun's family is rich, so I think they'd have lots of old stuff they don't need.
Well, yeah. We only like the
absolute newest stuff, after all.
If you have things you don't
need anymore, can we have them?
Sure.
Thanks!
What're you gonna do with stuff like this?
Its... a... secret.
I can't tell you, Suneo-kun, because you're so stingy.
If I told you how we're going to make it all new again with the Time Cloth...
You'll just take everything back, won't you?
That's why I won't tell you!
You're telling me everything.
We've gathered it all up!
Doraemon, hurry and use the Time Cloth on it!
Okay~!
There we go!
Whoa! That's amazing!
Hey... We've made it all new, but there are things here we don't want, right?
Yeah...
What if we sold those things?
But I don't know about
selling stuff we got for free...
If we made a profit, you
could buy some dorayaki, too.
D-D-Dorayaki?!
I wonder how many I could buy...
I don't know... Maybe 10 or 20?
20 of them?
Then, then... If we gathered up more stuff?
Then you could buy more.
And if we gathered up even more than that?
Then you could buy even more.
Then if we gathered up
more and more and more...
You could buy as many as you like.
Whoa! As many as I like?!
Then let's get more!
Let's gather up piles, and heaps,
truckloads, and mountains of stuff!
Hurry, hurry!
Okay.
I'm borrowing this for a bit.
Gouda General Store
Yo, Suneo.
Wut is it? I'm helpin' ma' Ma now.
Hey, I'd like to have any old junk
you don't need anymore, if you have any.
Here.
What...?
This really IS a bunch of junk.
Did ya' say sumthin' just now?
Ah, no! Just thanking you for your generosity.
'Ey, Suneo. Wutcha gonna do wid dat stuff?
It's... a... secret.
If I told Gian, he'd cause so much trouble. He's bossy and greedy, after all...
Wut was dat?!
Fine, I'll tell you! I'll tell you!
Gather up, everyone!
Listen up! It dun matter wut
it is, jus bring your old junk 'ere!
Now, move out!
And make it snappy.
Yer gonna do it, too.
What?!
Ya' gotta problem wid dat?
No, no...
Den get yer butt goin'!
Bring me back a lotta stuff!
That's why I don't like this...
Wit dis, I dun need ta' worry
'bout my allowance no more!
Why you...!
What're you doing?
Didn't I tell you to help run the store?!
Ma, waitta sec! I can makka
killer profit right now! Oww...
Come on, I'm not half asleep.
Go deliver these eggs to Yamada-san's place.
Kinda dangerous, isn't it?
Since you've got a cloth there,
wrap them up with that.
Wut?
Wit dis?
Don't be so slow! Hurry it up!
Oh, alright...
Hurry and get going!
Will dese really be okay...?
Augh! Why'd I haffa open my big mouth?!
Wait! Wait, li'l chicks! Wait...
The Time Cloth's gone!
What?!
I hung it right here.
Someone must've taken it.
Come on...
What's with Gian?
Everyone brought their junk, just like he said.
Where'd he go?
And what do we do with all this now...?
Huh? Hey!
Is that...?!
It's the Time Cloth!
I'm not gonna let you get it that easily!
I'll take that.
Yay!
This time, it's mine for sure...!
All right!
Huh? Hey, what's going on?
Ah! How could this happen?!
Later!
Wait!
Please, give an old man a break...
Where do you think you two  are  going?!
Alright! Dere it is! Dere it is!
I'm not gonna let'cha git away again!
It's mine now!
Give that back!
Wait, Suneo! Give that cloth back!
No fair, Suneo! Open up!
Suneo, give back my Time Cloth!
And what might you need? Your incessant pounding is just driving me crazy!
Oh, my! My Sune-chama did that?
Oh, how embarrassing.
Please wait here a moment.
Oh, my! I did not know it was such an amazing cloth!
But you must return other people's belongings.
Aw...
But I think I shall use it
once before returning it!
No fair, Mom!
I shall make this alligator skin handbag new again.
All that is required is to
drape the cloth over it, correct?
Help us!
It is TOO  new!
Mini Theater
Nobita-kun, let's play with this!
What do we do with a rope?
Let's make it into the shape of a horse...
That looks weird!
Huh? W-Whoa!
And it'll start to move!
This is fun!
Giddy up!
Lettus try it, too!
Hey!
Alright! I'mma gonna make a snake!
We got ate!
Help us!
It's a make-believe train!
The Dandelions Fly Off into The Sky
The Dandelions Fly Off into The Sky!
Wow, that sure surprised me!
Oh? What did?
This thing here!
Look! Inside the case where you were keeping the rhinoceros beetle last year...
It's a dandelion!
A seed must have got blown into the case.
Okay, I'll go throw it away.
Hey, w-wait... Nobita-kun!
How could you possibly say something like that?!
Cold heartedly taking the life of
a flower that worked so hard to make it...
Don't exaggerate...
It's just a dandelion.
Now you listen to me!
Even a weed or the smallest bug has feelings, too...
You've gotta have a loving heart towards them.
Then that heart will begin
to commune with nature...
And they'll be able to
flourish and enrich humanity.
You understand?
Not at all.
Didn't think you would.
So let's try...
Fantasy Glasses
The Fantasy Glasses!
Here. Go ahead and put them on.
Now take a look at the dandelion.
Ah, it's crying! What's going on?!
That's because you said
you were going to throw it away.
What...?
When you put on those Fantasy Glasses...
They personify plants and animals like in fantasy novels and fairy tales, making humans be able to see and understand their emotions.
How mysterious...
I'm sorry. Please don't cry!
I won't say I'm going to throw you away anymore!
I know! I'll go replant you in the backyard.
There. I'll plant you right here.
Excuse me, but...
If possible, could you put me in a sunnier place...?
I-It spoke!
Yeah...
Things can talk to you while you're
wearing the Fantasy Glasses, too.
They can?
Thank you for being so kind to me!
No, it was nothing.
Aw, that must be nice.
That dandelion's getting all the attention...
I'm so thirsty...
Aren't you thirsty, too?
No fair.
So thirsty...
Yeah, me too!
Me, too... Please, give me some water.
It doesn't rain over here, and I can't last much longer!
I couldn't possibly ignore them after they say all that.
Don't just watch, come and help!
I can't hear anything.
Wow, Nobita's watering the plants?
You don't see that everyday.
Hey, look.
That lazy, good-for-nothing
Nobita's actually watering.
Next we'll see pigs flying.
Even the cats made fun of me...
They're not really speaking...
The glasses are just making the putting your heart's innermost thoughts into words.
Man, I'm done with these things!
It's best not to think about things too deeply, and only put them on to play once in a while.
Who needs them?
Ants!
Doraemon must be hiding
dorayaki in the closet again.
Okay, I'll try looking at them with the glasses.
Work! Work! Because if we're being lazy...
We'll regret it when winter comes!
And we don't want to be like Nobita!
Ah! Even the ants made fun of me...
What...?!
Nobita's...
Actually studying!
I wonder what happened to him.
Thank you!
Thank you, Nobita-san.
Everyone's happy now, right? No more complaints?
Thank you for the delicious water.
You're getting all thick and full of buds, aren't you?
Yes.
'Ey, Nobita!
We came to get you!
It's Gian and Suneo...
Nobita! Yer on our baseball team,
so hurry up 'n get out here!
We're taking the time to invite
someone who sucks as much as you!
So you better be grateful!
Like I'd go with them!
If they lose, they'll just say it was my fault, anyway.
Are you bad at baseball?
Huh?
Hey, Gian. It's getting late, so let's go.
Yer right. We'll be back!
If you're bad at it...
You just have to try that much harder!
Be quiet! Don't say such ignorant things!
Oh, no! The dandelion!
Help me!
Ah! Help me!
Are you okay?
Nobita-san...!
That's great! You bloomed so beautifully.
It's all thanks to you, Nobita-san.
You planted me in such a good spot,
and protected me from the storm...
You're a really kind, reliable boy, Nobita-san.
No, you're just saying that.
It was nothing, really.
Dora-chan...
Nobita's been talking to himself
a lot lately. I'm worried about him.
Nobita-kun, why don't you go out and play some baseball once in a while...
Or do something that'll
really get your body moving?
I'm making it a point not to
do things I'm not confident in.
Then... What are you confident in?
Um...
Nothing!
Nobita! Yer definitely gonna
come play baseball wit us today!
You're awful if you refuse again!
Wait up!
We'll be back!
Humans are so rude and violent...
Plants, on the other hand...!
Wow, what a nice hat!
Thank you.
These are my children.
Pretty soon, they'll all take a journey
out into the vastness of the world.
I see...
Oh look, a breeze is coming in!
Huh?
Bye, everyone!
No! I wanna be with you forever, Mommy!
You mustn't say things like that.
But I'm scared...
You can't run away just because you're scared!
Your brothers and sisters all gathered up their courage and flew off, didn't they?
Come on, little one. You can do it!
Catch the next breeze that comes along, okay?
I don't wanna! I don't wanna!
What, really?
That's right, little one.
Your Mommy came flying in here on a breeze, too.
Where from? Where was your Mommy planted, Mommy?
She was on a train platform
deep in a far, far away mountain...
One sunny day, my many brothers and sisters and I all flitted off, up into the never-ending sky together.
Weren't you scared?
Not one bit!
I had been looking forward to
my first journey out into the world.
When I got tired, I hitched a ride on the roof of a train...
And listened to the sound of it chugging along as I let it rock me into a peaceful afternoon nap.
When night came, I did get lonely and cry a bit...
But I always had the moon to comfort me.
And you know... I still remember
when I first saw the sea, even now.
The sea?
Yes!
It was so big and blue...
And the glistening waves were so beautiful.
Then I finally made it to this town...
And got blown into Nobita-san's room.
Are you glad you went on your jounrey, Mommy?
Yes, of course I am.
After all... It was thanks to that, that I was able to blossom into a beautiful flower...
And give birth to all my little ones, whom I love so much.
Mommy?
Yes?
Tomorrow, I'm going to go on a journey, too!
Okay...
I just got real sleepy for some reason...
Then, how about I sing you a lullabye?
Okay!
Here it comes!
Hey! Little boy!
I'm right here!
Are you okay?
Yep! It's not as scary as I thought it would be.
But where are you planning to go from here?
The world's so big... There might be lots of scary places out there, you know?
You're right...
But I'll gather up my courage, and try to do my best!
Then I'll be able to blossom into
a beautiful flower, somewhere.
Nobita-san, tell my Mommy
not to worry about me, okay?
All right.
Bye!
Take care, okay! Goodbye!
All right, bring it on!
Ya' better hit it!
This is our chance to have
a good winning percentage!
I guess I'll try joining in.